Bora Demircan

Product Marketing & Software Development

Feel free to contact me



Personal Blog

www.borademircan.com



Email Address

bd@borademircan.com



Mobile Number +90 532 464 99 59

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Aug 2017 - Present

@ Theme Gusta

Co-founder

www.themegusta.com

May 2020 - Present

@ Helpviser

Co-founder

www.helpviser.com

Jan 2020 - Present

@ Coffee Roasterz

Co-founder

www.coffeeroasterz.com

Jun 2017 - Dec 2018

@ Bodrum Genie

Partner

www.bodrumgenie.com

May 2014 - Sep 2017

@ Libertas Consultancy

Senior Consultant

Business Development, Marketing Consultancy, Change Management, Corporate Governance, Business Planning & Feasibillity Studies, Strategic Consulting, Management Consulting, New Business and Project Development, Mergers & Acquisitions (M&A)

Nov 2012 - April 2014

@ Hürriyet - Advertisement Group

Digital Projects & Business Development Supervisor

Developed, coordinated and maintained digital and 360 degree integrated advertisement projects within Hürriyet Dünyası in the Media Convergence Environment. Developed and maintained Hürriyet Interactive Media Kits. Involved in Requirements Analysis stage of Hürriyet 3.0 SoLoMo Project

June 2011 - Nov 2012

@ Synergy Istanbul Digital Marketing Agency

Chief Information Officer

Developed, coordinated and maintained digital and 360 degree integrated advertisement projects within Hürriyet Dünyası in the Media Convergence Environment. Developed and maintained Hürriyet Interactive Media Kits. Involved in Requirements Analysis stage of Hürriyet 3.0 SoLoMo Project

2004 - June 2011

@ MB Digital House

Marketing & Business Development Specialist

Creating systems for Smart Passive Income, Content Management System Development, Online Sales, PHP / jQuery Scripts Development, Web Interface Design and Development, Wordpress CMS Theme Development, CMS Theme Development, E-commerce Design, Development and Management, Web Design & Development, Social Media & Search Engine Marketing Services.

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

A professional career in various areas of the digital world, across different sectors, both in the technical and business side, including software programming, web interface design, project management, account management and business development. Comprehensive education on Economics, Computer Engineering and Informatics, 8 years of experience on different businesses, which has led to creative and analytical approach to solve real world problems with technology. Created several Softwares such as a Content Management Software used for creating advanced websites with e-Commerce capabilities, Inventory and Multimedia Management Softwares and sold worldwide online with support and project based add-on development, Worked in Hürriyet Advertisement Group, in Projects & Business Development Department, creating tailor made multi-channel projects within Hürriyet channels. Managed projects within top brands in the Communication, Electronic Goods, Automotive, Education and Healthcare sectors.

SOCIAL NETWORK



facebook.com/borademircan



twitter.com/borademircan



linkedin.com/in/borademircan

LANGUAGES

- Turkish (Native)
- English (Full Professional Proficiency)

PERSONAL

- Date of Birth: 05 / 10 / 1980
- City of Birth: Ankara / TURKEY



2006-2007

@ EkoPLC Communication Tech. Inc.

Analyst & Developer

Involved in research and documentation of new technologies concerning hospitality market. Developed business plans for several projects. Involved in research and documentation of Supply Chain Management Systems and supporting tools. Involved in several PLC Network Design Projects for hotels. Branding, Web Design

EDUCATION

2006 - 2009

@ Middle East Technical University

Ms. in Informatics

Informatics Institute

2005 - 2006

@ TOBB ETU

Ms. in Computer Engineering

Completed Scientific Provision Classes, Operating Systems and Data Structures.

1998 - 2005

@ Bilkent University

Bs. in Economics

Faculty of Economics, Administrative and Social Sciences

1990-1997

@ TED Ankara College

Private Foundation High School

TRAINING

New York

@ INTEROP

CIO Bootcamp

The CIO Boot Camp blends ahead-of-the-curve leadership research with top-of-tech-trenches practical know-how in a highly interactive workshop designed to giving participants a fully rounded toolkit to meet the challenges of the current

Ankara

@ Turkish International Trade Assoc.

International Trade Expert Training Program

Certificate program dealing with all aspects including entrepreneurship, global trade organizations, export initiative programs, analysis of different markets, customs, insurance, freight, e-trade, communication techniques, preparation of documents and letters and general financing of international

Ankara

@ Middle East Technical University

Informatics Institute

E-business Environment and Architecture, IT Governance , COBIT Framework, Database Concept and Applications, Software Quality and Management, Web Services.

SKILLS & EXPERTISE

- Business Development
- · Project Management
- Mobile Marketing
- Dijital Media
- Website Design
- Web Programming
- Integrated Marketing
- · Search Engine Marketing
- Social Media Marketing
- Media Planning
- Web Analytics
- CMS Development
- Wordpress
- Digital Publishing
- Print Advertising
- New Media
- E-commerce Development
- E-commerce Management
- Marketing Strategy
- Financial Analysis
- Systems Analysis & Design
- Management Consultancy
- Budgeting & Forecasting
- Cost Analysis
- User Experience Design
- Mobile Web Design
- Web Applications
- Branding
- Research & Surveys
- Competitive Analysis
- Risk Assessment / Impact Analysis
- Public Relations
- Initiative Consultancy
- Incentive Programs Consultancy
- Database Development
- International Trade
- Professional Photography
- Corporate Identity
- Product Design
- Customer Interaction
- Regulatory Adherence
- Video Production & Editing